Guide to the Erving-King Family Papers 1709-1975 (bulk 1780-1939) MS 204
New-York Historical Society
Erving-King Family Papers
1709-1975 (bulk 1780-1939)
New-York Historical Society
King (Family)
MS 204
19 Linear Feet (36 boxes, 34 volumes)
The collection consists of correspondence, diaries, maps, printed matter, genealogical material, etc., assembled by James Gore King V (1898-1979). The collection concerns the Erving and King families, other families from whom he directly descended, and some collateral branches. The following individuals are comparatively well documented: James Gore King (1791-1853), Edward King (1833-1908), Col. John Erving (1789-1862), John Erving (1833-1917), and William Van Rensselaer (1805-1872).
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Historical Note
This collection, assembled by James Gore King V (1898-1979), records the history of his family from mid-eighteenth century to 1959 and traces his genealogy in America, Great Britain and Europe. The papers concern the Erving and King families; other families from whom JGK directly descended, and some collateral branches and connecting families are included. The papers of Fanny King [Mrs. Edmund] Ward were added in March 1980 by Mrs. Edmund M. Cocec.
The progenitors of James Gore King V's mother and father were early New England settlers. John Erving (1692-1786) made a fortune as a merchant in Boston. Richard King (1718-1775), son of John King, became a wealthy trader in the District of Maine. Many of their descendents and relatives were prominent in politics, diplomacy, military service, law, business, banking and letters; particularly in Maine, New Hampshire, Massachusetts, New York, New Jersey, and Great Britain and Europe. Through circumstances of war, politics and marriage, the branches from whom JGK descended were established in and around New York City by the early nineteenth century. They were well-to-do, and connected by marriage with other distinguished and prominent New York families. Whether at home or on their frequent travels within the United States and abroad, they moved in the top social and political circles of their day.
The lives of five men are comparatively well documented in this collection. James Gore King (1791-1853) attended school in England and France while his father, Rufus King (1755-1827), was ambassador to London. After graduating from Harvard and studying law, he became a banker, and in 1818 with his brother-in-law, Archibald Gracie, established in Liverpool the firm of King and Gracie. Returning to New York in 1824, he became a partner in what became Prime, Ward and King, and built the family home, Highwood, in Weehawken, N.J. During the panic of 1837, he personally secured in England enough gold to enable the United States to resume specie payment. He was also active in politics and railroad development. His third son, Edward King (1833-1908), attended Harvard and while in Cambridge lived with the Agassiz family. He and his first wife, Isabella Cochrane, were married in Edinburgh in 1858. He became president of the Union Trust Co. and of the New York Stock Exchange and was active in the Harvard Club of New York. Col. John Erving (1789-1862), a career officer in the United States Army, served in the war of 1812 and the Mexican War. He was popular with his men, and with hostesses at his Army posts. When not accompanying him, his wife, Emily Sophia Langdon-Elwyn, and their children lived in Philadelphia; then settled in New York. Their son, John Erving (1833-1917), graduated from Harvard in 1853 and became a lawyer in New York. He managed the financial affairs of his family. He served in the Army during the Civil War and in 1862 married Cornelia Van Rensselaer. Their principal home was at Manursing Island, Rye, N.Y., where the Van Rensselaers also lived. William Van Rensselaer (1805-1872), Cornelia's father, was the second son of Stephen Van Rensselaer, "eighth patroon" of vast land holdings in Albany and Rensselaer Counties. He graduated from Yale in 1824, traveled and studied law in Europe, and after the death of his first wife in 1836 married her sister Sarah Rogers. He managed his estates from his home, Beverwyck, across the Hudson from Albany, until 1846, when the family moved to New York City and Manursing Island. The younger John Erving and Edward King were classmates at Harvard. They became the grandfathers of James Gore King V.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence (mostly among family members), diaries and journals (many from trips abroad), and various legal and financial documents (particularly wills). It is concentrated in the period from about 1795 to World War I. The papers delineate personal and social lives; they deal to a much lesser extent with public, political and business affairs. They document many aspects of the lives of women and men: birth, marriage and death, daily activities and events, visits and travels, and interpersonal relations among families and friends.
The collection contains many individual manuscripts relating to prominent historical figures. However, most papers of the best-known members of the Erving and King families (Rufus King, for example) are in other collections; those that are in this collection are, with some exceptions, copies.
There is voluminous genealogical material, much in the form of repetitious handwritten notations. The genealogies of connecting families are often indispensable to identifying individuals mentioned in the collection. There are also inventories of personal property, memorabilia, such as invitations, visiting cards, drawings and paintings, maps, pamphlets, newspapers, clippings, and photographs of people, of family homes and monuments, of family portraits, and of places visited.
Unless specified in the inventory as copies (typed copies, manuscript copies or photocopies), documents are assumed to be original.
Arrangement
The Erving-King Papers are divided into three series. Series III, Oversize Materials, is divided into three subseries.
Within Series I and Series II, individuals' papers are arranged alphabetically by first name, related families follow alphabetically by surname. Some volumes are placed with the individual; most are at the end of the series.
The Erving-King papers are divided into the following three series:
Missing Title
Series I: Erving and related families
Series II: King and related families
Series III: Oversize Materials
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
Further information about the Erving and King families is located at the New-York Historical Society within the
Rufus King Papers
and the King Family Papers.
New York (N.Y.); Diaries.; Genealogies; Maps; Erving, Cornelia Van Rensselaer; Erving, John, 1789-1862; Erving, John, 1833-1917; Irwin (Family); King, Edwd. (Edward), 1833-1908; King, James G. (James Gore), 1791-1853; King, James Gore, 1898-1979; Van Rensselaer, William Paterson, 1805-1872
- Series I: Erving and Related Families
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of diaries, letters, genealogical and other papers of the Erving family and related families.
  - Family Genealogical Notes, 1838-1929, Undated (Box 1, Folder E1-A)
  - Family Genealogical Notes, 1914-1955, Undated (Box 1, Folder E1-B)
  - Abigail Erving, correspondence, including note of her death, 1844 Mar.-1850 Aug. (Box 1, Folder E2-A)
  - Abigail Erving, correspondence, 1826 Mar.-1843 Dec. (Box 1, Folder E2-B)
  - Ann (Shaeffe) Erving, correspondence sent by friends, 1781 Feb.-1786 May, Undated (Box 1, Folder E3)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, diaries, journals, cards, death notices, 1860-1913 (Box 1, Folder E4)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, correspondence sent to family, friends, 1861-1913 (Box 1, Folder E5)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, correspondence sent to Grace and Fanny Schuyler, 1869-1890 (Box 2, Folder E6)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, correspondence sent to Cornelia V. R. Pruyn, 1895 Nov.-1896 Sept. (Box 2, Folder E7)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, correspondence, speeches, notes relating to Causeries de Lundi, 1894-1913 (Box 2, Folder E8-A)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, speeches, notes, publications relating to Causeries de Lundi, 1889-1930 (Box 2, Folder E8-B)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, poetry, prose, other writings, 1878-1913, Undated (Box 2, Folder E9-A)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, poetry, prose, other writings, Undated (Box 2, Folder E9-B)
  - Cornelia V. R. Erving, poetry, prose, other writings, 1892, Undated (Box 2, Folder E9-C)
  - Edward S. Erving, correspondence sent to John Irving, poetry, 1814-1835 (Box 3, Folder E10)
  - Eleanor C. Erving, correspondence, diary, will, clippings relating to Women's Suffrage, 1911-1953 (Box 3, Folder E11)
  - Elwyn Erving, Army papers, correspondence, 1861-1863 (Box 3, Folder E12)
  - Emily S. (Langdon-Elwyn) Erving, correspondence, will, 1834-1864, [1868] (Box 3, Folder E13)
  - Frances A. Erving, correspondence sent to John Erving Family, will, 1859-1880 (Box 3, Folder E14)
  - George Erving, correspondence; Promissory notes, in Dutch, 1774-1799 (Box 3, Folder E15)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Includes some photocopies
  - George William Erving, genealogical notes, correspondence, clippings, picture, will, 1801-1850 (Box 3, Folder E16-A)
  - George William Erving, correspondence relating to his death, 1850-1852 (Box 3, Folder E16-B)
  - George William Erving, correspondence with James Monroe, 1802-1816, Undated (Box 3, Folder E16-C)
    Photocopies
  - John Erving I, biographical information, correspondence, wills, 1764, 1784, Undated (Box 3, Folder E17)
  - John Erving I, 2 volumes manuscipt record books related to will and estate, 1784, 1791 (Box 3, Folder E18)
  - John Erving II, correspondence, will, pocket Almanac, 1774-1815 (Box 3, Folder E19)
  - John Erving III, correspondence with friends and family, 1787 Mar.-1835 Mar. (Box 4, Folder E20-A)
  - John Erving III, correspondence, legal and business papers, 1775-1863 (Box 4, Folder E20-B)
  - John Erving III, manuscript: translation of Rousseau's On Education, Undated (Box 4, Folder E21)
  - Col. John Erving IV, Military papers and commissions, 1812-1849, Undated (Box 4, Folder E22-A)
  - Col. John Erving IV, Military papers and commissions, 1844-1859, Undated (Box 4, Folder E22-B)
  - Col. John Erving IV, Military commissions signed by various U.S. Presidents, 1812-1858, Undated (Box 4, Folder E22-C)
  - Col. John Erving IV, correspondence, clippings, 1818-1862 (Box 4, Folder E23-A)
  - Col. John Erving IV, financial accounts, correspondence with Henry Burroughs, 1836-1872 (Box 5, Folder E23-B)
  - Col. John Erving IV, invitations, including to Lafayette, 1820-1856 (Box 5, Folder E24)
  - John Erving V, school work, correspondence, biographical information, 1841-1917 (Box 5, Folder E25-A)
  - John Erving V, correspondence with family, 1846-1849 (Box 5, Folder E25-B)
  - John Erving V, correspondence sent to parents, mostly from Harvard, 1850-1851 (Box 5, Folder E26-A)
  - John Erving V, correspondence sent to parents, material from Harvard including reference letter from Jared Sparks, 1852-1855 (Box 5, Folder E26-B)
  - John Erving V, correspondence, 1855-1856 (Box 5, Folder E27-A)
  - John Erving V, correspondence, 1857-1859 (Box 5, Folder E27-B)
  - John Erving V, correspondence, 1860-1865 (Box 5, Folder E28)
  - John Erving V, correspondence, memorandum books, clippings, 1879-1913 (Box 6, Folder E29)
  - John Erving V, correspondence, souvenirs from trip abroad, 1857 (Box 6, Folder E30)
  - John Erving V, 6 account books, 1857 (Box 6, Folder E31)
  - John Erving V, military papers, soldier's prayer book, 1861-1868, 1917 (Box 6, Folder E32)
  - John Erving V, papers regarding Harvard Class of 1853, 1850-1909 (Box 6, Folder E33)
  - John Erving V, decendents, 1916, Undated (Box 6, Folder E34-A)
  - John Erving V, Articles of Agreement with Nathan W. Riker; Indenture with Emily Sophia Erving, 1864, 1869 (Box 6, Folder E34-B)
  - J. Langdon Erving Family, correspondence, photographs, 1866-1933 (Box 6, Folder E35)
  - Langdon Erving, will, 1862 (Box 6, Folder E36)
  - Maria C. Erving, account book, correspondence, 1756-1806 (Box 6, Folder E37)
  - W. Shirley Erving, correspondence, 1903-1928 (Box 6, Folder E38)
  - William V.R. Erving, correspondence, letters of condolence, clippings, 1910-1940 (Box 7, Folder E39)
  - Catherine V.R. Atterbury, correspondence, 1871-1929 (Box 7, Folder E40-A)
  - Catherine V.R. Atterbury, correspondence, 1871-1929 (Box 7, Folder E40-A)
  - Catherine V.R. Atterbury, Papers regarding Causeries de Lundi and Society of Colonial Dames, wills, inventories, 1920-1930 (Box 7, Folder E40-B)
  - Bayard Family, genealogy, biographies, correspondence, 1753-1885, Undated (Box 7, Folder E41)
  - Bowdoin Family, genealogy, correspondence, 1826, 1914, Undated (Box 7, Folder E42)
  - Bowdoin Family, genealogy, correspondence, 1826, 1914, Undated (Box 7, Folder E42)
  - Cooper Family, genealogy, correspondence, invitations, 1859-1955, Undated (Box 7, Folder E43)
  - Cruger Family, correspondence, poems, wills, 1839-1923 (Box 7, Folder E44)
  - Elwyn Family, correspondence, genealogy, military papers, financial papers, 1806-1948 (Box 7, Folder E45)
  - Eleanor V. R. Fairfax, correspondence, clippings, invitations, 1875-1892 (Box 7, Folder E46)
  - Langdon Family, correspondence, proclamations, 1777-1902 (Box 7, Folder E47)
  - Langdon Family, genealogy, material relating to Langdon home in Portsmouth, N.H., 1948, Undated (Box 7, Folder E48)
  - Elizabeth Langdon Elwyn, correspondence, will, 1818-1851 (Box 8, Folder E49)
  - Joanna Livingston, correspondence sent to Ann Shaeffe, [1780-1790] (Box 8, Folder E50)
  - Alida Livingston, correspondence sent to Ann Shaeffe, [1780-1790] (Box 8, Folder E51)
  - Pruyn-Hoppin Family, genealogy, correspondence, [1890-1900] (Box 8, Folder E52)
  - Paterson Family, genealogical notes, correspondence, 1780-1931, Undated (Box 8, Folder E53)
  - Rogers Family, genealogical notes, correspondence, 1809-1839 (Box 8, Folder E54)
  - Benjamin Woolsey Rogers, genealogical notes, correspondence, 1815-1839 (Box 8, Folder E55)
  - Benjamin Woolsey Rogers, journals, 1796, 1801 (Box 8, Folder E56-A)
    4 Volumes
  - Benjamin Woolsey Rogers, journals, 1814-1815 (Box 8, Folder E56-B)
    5 Volumes
  - Benjamin Woolsey Rogers, journals, 1831, 1834-1835 (Box 8, Folder E56-C)
    3 Volumes
  - Schuyler Family, correspondence with William and Sarah Van Rennselaer, 1841-1887 (Box 9, Folder E57)
  - Shaeffe Family, correspondence, genealogical notes, 1774, 1850, Undated (Box 9, Folder E58)
  - Helen and Maria Shaeffe, correspondence to Ann Shaeffe Erving, 1784-1793 (Box 9, Folder E59)
  - Sir Roger Hale Shaeffe, correspondence to John and Ann Erving and to John and Frances Erving, 1789-1850 (Box 9, Folder E60)
  - Shirley Family, genealogy, correspondence, 1731-1905, Undated (Box 9, Folder E61)
  - Shirley Family, papers, genealogical notes, correspondence, 1745-1843, Undated (Box 9, Folder E62)
    Includes one monograph, The Conduct of Major General Shirley.... London: R. & J. Dodsley, 1758.
  - Shirley Family, papers of Lord Charles Western, 1767-1844 (Box 9, Folder E63)
  - Van Rensselaer Family, genealogical and biographical notes, 1839-1949 (Box 9, Folder E64-A)
  - Van Rensselaer Family, clippings, pamphlets, postcards, photographs, genealogy, 1873-1968 (Box 9, Folder E64-B)
  - Van Rensselaer Family, fragments of family Bible, genealogical notes, 1762-1906 (Box 9, Folder E65)
  - Van Rensselaer Family, Petitions and speeches regarding Livingston Manor, 1795-1815 (Box 9, Folder E66)
  - Van Rensselaer Family, correspondence, invitations, 1852-1891 (Box 9, Folder E67)
  - Cornelia P. Van Rensselaer, correspondence to William and Sarah V.R., to Harmanus Bleecker, 1833-1844 (Box 9, Folder E68)
  - Kiliaen Van Rensselaer and family, correspondence, biographical notes, clippings, copies of Civil War correspondence, 1864-1927 (Box 10, Folder E69-A)
    Includes some typed copies
  - Kiliaen Van Rensselaer and family, poetry and photographs, 1901, Undated (Box 10, Folder E69-B)
  - Sarah R. Van Rensselaer, correspondence, poetry, clippings, notebook, will, 1835-1887 (Box 10, Folder E70)
  - Sarah R. Van Rensselaer, correspondence to Grace and Fanny Schuyler, 1847-1852 (Box 10, Folder E71-A)
  - Sarah R. Van Rensselaer, correspondence to Grace and Fanny Schuyler, 1853-1887 (Box 10, Folder E71-B)
  - Sarah R. Van Rensselaer, correspondence, clippings, genealogical notes, 1886-1888 (Box 10, Folder E72-A)
  - Sarah R. Van Rensselaer, manuscripts "The Tories of the American Revolution," and "Ancestral Biographical Sketches from 1608-1840", Undated (Box 10, Folder E72-B)
  - Omitted (Box 10, Folder E73)
  - Stephen Van Rensselaer, correspondence, will, engraved portrait, 1782-1839 (Box 10, Folder E74-A)
  - Stephen Van Rensselaer III, correspondence, records, 1826-1888 (Box 10, Folder E74-B)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Stephen Van Rensselaer III, funeral discourses, 1839,1844 (Box 11, Folder E75)
  - Susan B. Van Rensselaer, correspondence, copy books, poetry, 1850-1861 (Box 11, Folder E76)
  - William P. Van Rensselaer, correspondence, biographical notes, correpsondence, letters of introduction, 1827-1872 (Box 11, Folder E77)
  - William P. Van Rensselaer, family correspondence, 1851-1867 (Box 11, Folder E78-A)
  - William P. Van Rensselaer, family correspondence, 1854-1872 (Box 11, Folder E78-B)
  - William P. Van Rensselaer, speeches, legal documents, calendar, clippings, 1849-1869 (Box 11, Folder E79-A)
  - William P. Van Rensselaer, will, court papers, financial papers, 1872-1916 (Box 11, Folder E79-B)
  - William P. Van Rensselaer, lecture notes, diaries, 1828-1868 (Box 11, Folder E80-A)
    Includes 1 volume
  - William P. Van Rensselaer, diaries, 1827-1870 (Box 11, Folder E80-B)
    5 volumes
  - William Stephen Van Rensselaer, correspondence with Justine Erving and others, 1897-1929 (Box 12, Folder E81)
  - Erving and related families, documents and other manuscripts regarding the estates of John Erving, William Erving, Justine Erving, Emily S. Erving, Moses Rogers, Anson Atterbury, 1775-1959 (Box 12, Folder E82-A)
  - Erving and related families, wills and documents relating to the estates of John Erving, William P.R. Van Rensselaer, Elizabeth Langdon Elwyn and Cornelia Cruger, 1867-1929 (Box 12, Folder E82-B)
  - Erving, King and related families, stories, drawings, correspondence, Undated (Box 12, Folder E82-C)
  - Erving and related families, documents regarding Manursing Island home and Greenwood Cemetery plots, 1878-1951 (Box 12, Folder E83)
  - Erving and related families, inventories and appraisals, 1834-1925 (Box 12, Folder E84)
  - Erving and related families, correspondence, documents, 1834-1959 (Box 12, Folder E85)
  - Erving family memorabilia, invitations, calling cards, recipes, 1834-1959 (Box 12, Folder E86)
  - Erving family, items unconnected to specific family members, Undated (Box 12, Folder E87)
  - Erving family, drawings, watercolors, silhouettes, 1813-1833, Undated (Box 12, Folder E88)
  - Erving family, pamphlets, sermons, almanacs, 1837-1902 (Box 13, Folder E89)
  - Erving family, newspaper clippings, 1764 Oct.-1797 Dec. (Box 13, Folder E90-A)
  - Erving family, newspaper clippings, 1840-1847 (Box 13, Folder E90-B)
  - Erving family, newspaper clippings, 1851-1854 (Box 13, Folder E90-C)
  - Erving family, newspaper clippings, including account of Lincoln's funeral, 1862-1865 (Box 13, Folder E90-D)
  - Erving family, maps, 1789, Undated (Box 13, Folder E91)
  - Erving family, published letters by Washington, Adams, Jefferson and others, 1880 (Box 13, Folder E92)
  - Erving family, tributes and memorials, 1774-1930 (Box 13, Folder E93)
  - Erving family, publications and addresses of the Order of Colonial Lords of Manors in America, 1916-1938 (Box 13, Folder E94)
  - Erving family, histories and genalogies of the Bowdoin, Bayard, Houstoun and Bolton families, 1894, 1919 (Box 13, Folder E95)
  - Erving Family, Volumes
    - An Oration...in commemoration of Thomas Jefferson and John Adams by John Sergeant, 1826 (Box 13, Folder E96)
    - God's Way in the Deep by Dr. Cortlandt Van Rensselaer, 1854 (Box 13, Folder E96)
  - Official Army Register, 1815-1862 (Box 14, Folder E97)
    12 volumes
  - The Army List, 1840, 1843, 1846, 1860, 1864 (Box 14, Folder E98)
  - Erving Family, Volumes
    - The Replie of John Darrell, to the Answer of John Deacon...., 1602 (Box 14, Folder E99)
    - The Life of His Excellency, Sir William Phips, Knt., 1697 (Box 14, Folder E99)
    - A Sermon on Domestic Happiness by the Reverand Thomas Franklin, A.M., 1765 (Box 14, Folder E99)
    - Reflections...on the letters of the Late Earl of Chesterfield by Thomas Hunter, M.A., 1780 (Box 14, Folder E99)
  - Erving Family, Volumes
    - The Revolution of America by the Abbe Raynal, 1782 (Box 14, Folder E100)
    - Observations on the Importance of the American Revolution, 1784 (Box 14, Folder E100)
    - Substance of the Report of the Sierra Leone Company, 1794 (Box 14, Folder E100)
    - The Three Brothers...., 1825 (Box 14, Folder E100)
    - King-Caucus, or Secrets Worth Knowing...., [1824] (Box 14, Folder E100)
  - Thomas Elwyn, Latin Exercise Book, 1791 (Volume E1)
  - Ship's Log: Frigate Macedonian, James Biddle, Commander. (T.O. Langdon-Elwyn was midshipman aboard.), 1826 June-1827 Sept. (Volume E2)
  - Emily Sophia (Langdon-Elwyn) [Mrs. John] Erving, diary, 1835 Aug.-1837 July (Volume E3)
  - John Erving V, diary, 1854 July-1860 Dec. (Volume E4)
  - John Erving V, Justine Erving, songbook, 1858, 1898 (Volume E5)
  - John Erving V, scrapbook with clippings, 1856-1863 (Volume E6)
  - Catherine G. (VanRensselaer) Atterbury, copybook (poetry), 1863 Oct. (Volume E7)
  - Catherine G. (VanRensselaer) Atterbury, scrapbook with clippings, engravings, Confederate currency, 1864 Nov. (Volume E8)
  - Catherine G. (VanRensselaer) Atterbury, travel journal - Ireland, Scotland, England, Italy, Egypt, 1869 (Volume E9)
  - Catherine G. (VanRensselaer) Atterbury, travel journal - Egypt, Holy Land, Syria, Turkey, Greece, Cyprus, Italy, 1870 (Volume E10)
  - Catherine G. (VanRensselaer) Atterbury, travel journal - Europe, 1870 (Volume E11)
  - Catherine G. (VanRensselaer) Atterbury, travel journal - Britain, 1870 (Volume E12)
  - Catherine G. (VanRensselaer) Atterbury, travel journal - Europe, 1873-1874 (Volume E13)
  - Sarah R. VanRensselaer, Ancestral Sketches. New York: Randolph., 1882 (Volume E14)
  - Erving and related families, letterbook (disbound), documents, 1742-1798, 1805-1872 (Volume E15)
  - John Erving I, letterbook, 1769-1786 (Volume E16)
  - Eleanor Cecilia Erving, diaries, 1938-1940, 1943-1944, 1946 (Volume E17)
  - Eleanor Cecilia Erving, quotations, Undated (Volume E18)
  - Washington's Letters on Agriculture awarded to William P. VanRensselaer by the Rensselaer County Agricultural Society, 1845 (Volume E19)
  - American Genealogy by Jerome Holgate, A.M. Albany: Munsell, 1848 (Volume E20)
  - Annals of the Shirley Family... Westminster: J.B. Nichols, 1841 (Volume E21)
  - Histoire de Bayard, Undated (Volume E22)
- Series II: King and Related Families
  Consists of diaries, letters, genealogical and other papers of the King family and related families.
  Note: The collection does not contain volumes K5 and K6.
  - Genealogical notes, 1831-[1962] (Box 15, Folder K1-A)
  - Genealogical notes, 1913-1975, Undated (Box 15, Folder K1-B)
  - Charles King, biographical notes, correspondence, published lectures, 1816-1856 (Box 15, Folder K2)
  - Charles King, correspondence, [1825-1863] (Box 15, Folder K3)
    Manuscript copies and photocopies